[Music]
in my video the benefits of fenu Greek
seeds I profiled this study in which
young men were randomized to a sugar
pill or fenu Greek capsules for eight
weeks and got a significant Improvement
in upper body strength lower body
strength and body composition a
significant reduction in body fat
percentage and the only side effect it
can make your sweat and peace smell like
maple syrup seems like a
bonus studies on immature castrated rats
suggest the fenugreek muscle bulking is
a testosterone effect but we didn't know
what happens in humans
until now for randomized control trials
put it to the test and saw a significant
boost of total blood testosterone and
indeed fenu Greek appears to improve
sexual function in men for example
doubling the frequency of morning
erections what about the sexual function
in women while the estrogen hormone
estradiol stimulates vaginal lubrication
and blood flow facilitating a woman's
capacity for sexual arousal and orgasm
it's the testosterone that's linked with
sexual desire in both men and women drug
companies have tried testosterone
patches on women to try to increased
sexual desire but we're concerned about
blood clots and long-term safety what
about a little fenu greek a significant
increase in testosterone compared to
Placebo and a boost in the estrogen
estradiol which resulted in both an
increase in sexual desire and function
translating to about a doubling of
sexual activity compared to
Placebo if fenugreek causes an increase
in estrogen levels what about the
efficacy of fenugreek for reducing menop
AAL symptoms a significant reduction in
menopausal symptoms across every single
domain for example cutting the weekly
numbers of hot flashes and night sweats
in half over a period of 3 months other
hormonal effects include an improvement
in painful periods what I like about
this study is that they didn't use some
proprietary extract but just straight
plain fenugreek powder that you'd you
know buy at the store now they packed it
into capsules just so they could pit it
against a sugar pill Placebo but the
dose they used is about a third of a
teaspoon three times a day taken the
first 3 days of their period a third of
a teaspoon would cost less than 5 cents
and boom significant decrease in pain
and also appeared to improve other
symptoms as well while we're on a roll
with hormonal effects what about the
effectiveness of fenugreek as a galactic
Gog no not another sci-fi reboot a
galactic Gog is something that increas
re's breast milk production in lactating
mothers and fenu Greek fits the bill and
not just by a little in this randomized
double blind Placebo control trial in
which breastfeeding women took less than
a quar teaspoon of fener Greek less than
a quar teaspoon of ground ginger and
about a 16th of a teaspoon of turmeric
every day doubled their milk production
within a month about a 50% increase by
week two and 100% increase by week
four however due to potential
stimulation on the uterus Fu Greek seeds
should not be used during pregnancy
though this is all based on laboratory
animal data better safe than
[Music]
sorry for